Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
Kimi yo hashire
You must run forth!
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Kyodai na teki o
You must fight the towering foe!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Kimi yo tsukame
You must seize the power!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
A half-century has passed since humanity began moving...
...its burgeoning population into space.
These gigantic space colonies orbiting the Earth...
...became a second home to humanity...
...where people were born and raised...
...and where they died.
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The cluster of colonies furthest from Earth, known as Side 3...
...proclaimed themselves the Principality of Zeon.
And launched a war of independence against the Earth Federation.
In roughly one month of fighting, the Principality of Zeon...
...and the Federation Forces caused the deaths of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
Vote to Attack!
Luna II...
An asteroid placed in
the moon's orbital path...
...to provide construction
materials for the space colonies.
Once you've made contact with Luna II...
...you can request permission to enter port in my name.
Commandant Wakkein will
handle things from there.
You must rest, sir.
I'll get some painkillers...
It's all right.
We have canned food for you!
How many are in here?
Seven, I think.
Excuse me, I asked for some hot water
to warm the milk earlier...
Here it is!
How long until we get to Luna II?
About one hour.
Excuse me.
When will the food rations come?
They're coming down the hall.
Ms. Sayla!
Where did you live
before coming to Side 7?
Do I have to answer that?
Uh, no.
Earth.
This is my first time...
Huh?
Out in space, that is.
So you're one of the elite.
Are you being sarcastic?
You need to grow a tougher skin, Mr. Bright.
I'll take over for you.
I just need to watch the gauges?
I'd appreciate it if you could, until we dock.
Sure.
They're still there.
I think it's just a matter of time.
What is?
Char's attack.
A Papua-class supply ship? Such an old ship
can't carry all the supplies we need.
Be realistic.
But...
We don't have the extra resources
we did in the past.
Char, I sent two Zakus.
Get me the Federation's top secrets
even if you have to sacrifice the Musai!
Yes, sir.
I requested three, but this is what I get.
And we still don't know
the full capabilities of their mobile suit.
Amuro! Amuro! Where are you?
Fraw Bow! He's in the Gundam's cockpit.
Again?
Amuro.
I brought you food and fresh clothes.
You'll start to stink.
And you're hardly eating, Amuro.
You've got to take time to eat.
I don't want to eat.
Don't get so upset because of Bright.
That's got nothing to do with it.
I'm doing this because I don't want to die.
Is that so.
Yeah.
Why do you think Char's Musai
hasn't attacked us yet?
They're probably still uncertain
of the White Base's capabilities.
And also...
They could have used up
all their weapons.
Sure. However...
However...?
It may be a ploy to make us think that way.
A ship is approaching Char's Musai!
Reinforcements?!
Not sure. They will dock in 15 minutes.
Maybe it's just as Mirai said.
We can't assume that.
What if it's a battle cruiser?
Before they supply weapons
to Char's Musai...
...we and Amuro
should be able to fight them.
You want to launch an attack?
If Char strikes again, do you think
we can survive, Mr. Bright?
We don't even have
one regular combatant.
Operator! How long will it take the enemy
to transfer supplies between ships?
If it's just weapons, then 10 minutes.
So we'd have a total of 25 minutes.
Why don't you ask the captain?
I don't like your tone of voice. Cut it out.
What do you think, Hayato?
Sir, however big the opponent may be...
...if he's wobbling or off-balance...
then we can topple him.
That's what I learned in judo class.
Ms. Mirai! Get everyone on the bridge!
Emergency announcement!
All combat-capable individuals
report to the bridge...
Irrespective of age...
Hey!
Yes sir!
Excluding engineers, all personnel...
Kikka, you stay in the room!
We're all supposed to go, aren't we?
I'll wash these for you!
Thanks.
There's no time to get everyone's opinion.
We'll decide by vote.
First, we only have a 50/50 chance
of pulling this off...
...but those who are in favor
of making a run for the Luna II base...
...raise your hands.
I count five votes.
Next, this is also a 50/50 chance, but...
...those in favor of launching an attack.
We should fight!
Yeah! We should fight!
Good, it's decided then. We'll attack.
Amuro, to the Gundam.
Ryu, to the Core Fighter.
We may have to use the Guntank as well.
Put the beam cannons on standby.
White Base, turn about 180 degrees!
Catapult connections complete.
Ryu, Core Fighter, okay to launch.
Output, 60... 70...!
...85... 120...!
Launching!
Core Fighter has been launched.
Amuro, prepare the Gundam for catapult.
Do you know how?
I think so. I'll give it a try.
Just like in the manual.
Catapult rig, check.
Gundam output, normal.
Here I go!
Proceed for 10 km...
...and descend to approach enemy
from behind the ridge. Understand?
Roger!
Roger that!
Prepare port and starboard beam cannons,
on the double!
Standing by to fire!
Energy pipes connected!
Forward main cannon lifts, okay!
Loading commencing!
We'll have visual contact in 8 minutes.
Until then, check your manuals again.
Just fire and give them cover.
But don't hit the Gundam
or the Core Fighter.
How can such a tired old ship
remain in active service?
Ensign Dren.
Yes, sir!
Open a video link with them.
Yes, sir.
The famous Red Comet wants supplies, eh?
You must have screwed up.
Gadem, the enemy's close. We must hurry!
I know that.
Do you really think I'm that slow?
I'm pretty swift for my age, you know.
Open the hatches!
Hurry up and dock the conveyor pipes!
Ready to receive conveyor pipes!
Ryu's a soldier. He should know better.
Don't ascend? But the enemy's right there!
Don't you realize that we'll be
facing the sun if we go in this way?!
We should go around.
Where's the Musai?
We should be able to see it any minute.
I see it now!
That Amuro's pretty clever for a novice.
So, he wants to attack
with the sun behind us.
Right. Let's go!
Conveyor pipe docking, complete!
Begin transfer of ammunition!
Char! Don't you think this is odd?
I know we're close to the enemy's
front-line base...
...but it's located on the opposite side.
The Minovsky particle density
seems too high.
I agree, Gadem.
An enemy ship nearby?
It's possible.
All right... I've got you now, Char.
Possible missile approaching from behind!
What?
Impact in 3 seconds!
3... 2... 1...!
Conveyor pipes were hit!
Separate the ship from the Musai!
Second missile approaching! 7... 6...!
Gadem, release the Zakus you brought!
Right! I'll do what I can!
2... 1...!
We have to deliver the Zakus to Char!
Matthew! Fix! Prepare to board the Zakus
outside of the ship!
I'll launch first in my mobile suit.
Launch all our small missiles horizontally!
Mobile Suit
Dren, cover the Papua.
The enemy is attacking with mobile suits,
not battleships.
Roger!
Turn about 180 degrees, hard!
Blocks with remaining missiles,
fire everything you have toward the sun.
How long until the mega particle cannons'
energy is recharged?
5 minutes, 20 seconds!
Damn! That's too slow!
We reduced main engine power too much.
A third missile approaching!
7... 6...!
5... 4...!
3... 2...!
I missed it.
I've had enough of this.
So the mobile suits are over there.
Incoming! Enemy fighter, port-stern!
Intercept it!
Descend!
We'll drop the supplies on Luna II!
Char!
Fighting strength isn't determined by
differences in mobile suit performance!
I'll teach you that!
Damn that Char!
All right!
Damn! The bazooka's out of ammo!
Behind me!
Too slow.
Lieutenant Commander Char!
The enemy's Trojan Horse is attacking us!
What?! Try to hold it off until I get there!
I'm not letting you hit our ship!
I promised Bright...
I... I have to keep Char occupied!
That damned Ryu!
Thanks to him, I can't fire the main cannons!
Hayato, is it? Pass on the message...
"Stay out of my way, Ryu!"
Yes!
But how do I contact the bridge...?
Hurry!
Descend and turn about 170 degrees!
Aim main cannons at enemy ship!
Yes, sir!
The Musai's not attacking us!
They can't use their mega particle cannons
during the resupply process. Besides...
...they have no missiles.
Altitude 300!
Musai descending to starboard!
Relative speed, 0.23 km/sec.
Estimated contact, 5.2 seconds.
Mr. Bright, I have a request.
What is it?
Mr. Kai can't aim at the Musai.
He says the Core Fighter is in the way.
Understood.
Ryu, come in! Ryu...!
What happened?
His comm circuit isn't connected.
So, we can't hit the enemy?!
Inexperienced pilot! Take this!
What?!
Amateur.
Stop!
Damn! That Federation mobile suit
is a monster!
How can it withstand this beating...?!
Lt. Commander Char, please return!
We can't use our
mega particle cannons, and...
Where are the Zakus?
Do you have them yet?!
The Papua's catapult has been damaged.
The Zakus aren't...
Grab the Zakus, even if that's all we get!
I'll be there! Just hold on!
Char!
Mr. Bright!
Mr. Kai says he has a special
large-vehicle license.
Huh?
His father is an engineer, so he...
I understand. He said a special license?
Yes! Don't we have
a tank-type mobile suit?
It's a two-man.
Like the main cannons on this ship, right?
I can fire it. They taught me how.
You want to approach them in the Guntank?
Yes, sir! They're distracted
by the White Base, so we'll be fine!
We can do it!
Do it.
Yes, sir!
What's taking you so long?!
At this rate, the Musai will be taken out!
Y-Yes, captain!
How is the Zaku launch coming along?!
W-We can't repair the catapult!
Idiots! Push it out manually, then!
Damn it!
Energy recharge completed!
Good! Prepare the mega particle cannons!
Kai! Hayato!
What's taking the Guntank so long?!
Fire on the enemy! Fire!
Stay calm, Mr. Bright!
The Guntank is about to
leave the White Base.
Ground speed, 12.5 meters/sec...
10 meters...
Kai Shiden, do you read me?
Head out in 3 seconds. All right?
I don't have any choice, do I?
Anytime.
Uh, Ms. Sayla, was it?
Don't waste time with small talk.
White Base, touchdown! Head out!
Please hurry, Mr. Kai!
The enemy is just over the ridge!
Don't yell! I'm having a hard enough time
making this thing run!
Hayato! Let's get this over with quickly!
Please proceed another 50 meters.
We'll definitely be within firing range.
What if they fire missiles at us?
They're resupplying, so I doubt they will.
But what if they do?
I don't know. 10 more meters...!
I'm going to fire!
Char's going to get his Zakus,
missiles, and food!
This is a matter of honor
for the supply corps!
Musai! You've got your Zakus!
Matthew! Fix! Get into the Zakus!
I won't let you!
That damned Red Comet!
Gadem, what about the supplies?
We dumped just about everything!
Retrieve them after you defeat the enemy!
Is that it?! The Federation's mobile suit?
Gadem, calm down!
Don't stop me!
They destroyed my ship!
Me and my Zaku have fought in
countless battles.
I'll destroy the Federation's
slapped-together mobile suit!
No weapon?!
Stop, Gadem!
You can't do it with your Zaku!
You novice! You tried to attack too soon!
I can't believe the Federation developed...
...a mobile suit like this!
G-Gadem!
Retreat, Amuro! Retreat!
We've destroyed the supply ship!
Retreat now!
But...
You don't have weapons left either, do you?
How are you going to fight Char?!
Char...
Roger!
The enemy mobile suit...
The Papua's destroyed. Gadem's dead.
How can this be?
The enemy mobile suit...
...and that ship.
It's clear we lost because
the Federation's new weapons...
...are so powerful.
I can understand that.
However...
...what does it all mean?
Their military tactics are awkward,
and they fight like amateurs.
Lieutenant Commander!
This is Matthew and Fix in the Zakus.
Shall we pursue the enemy?
Go cover the people loading the supplies.
Yes, sir. Proceeding immediately.
What does it mean?
Like they say, doing something
is better than worrying.
Don't be naive!
You were only able to attack in the Guntank
because Amuro kept Char distracted!
Hear that, Hayato?
I think it's true.
You brown-noser.
I'm sorry, Bright. Apparently
I had the communications disconnected.
Be careful next time.
Remember your training.
As for you, Amuro...
You try to outflank the enemy too much.
No. His maneuver was sound.
Right?
Yes. Char was just too quick, that's all.
Char is also known as the Red Comet.
You fought him once before.
Think a little more about your tactics.
Yes, sir!
All hands, take some rest while
maintaining level 2 battle stations...
Full speed ahead on course to
the Luna II front-line base.
All clear.
Mr. Ryu. I have the feeling that,
I'm gonna end up decking that guy!
Fraw Bow!
You must be exhausted.
I brought you some tea.
Well, well...
Good work, Amuro! Good work, Amuro!
You're sounding good, Haro.
What on earth is that?
I built it. It's called Haro.
Mine field, 25 km to port.
Course, 3.2 to starboard.
Amuro and the crew are detained
by the Federation Forces, their allies.
Meanwhile, Char and his commandos
sneak in...
...determined to destroy the Gundam.
Will Amuro and the crew have to fight
their own allies to free the White Base?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Escape from Luna II.
Next Time
Escape From Luna II
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...